type Question = {
  question: string;
  options: string[];
  answer: string;
};

export const questionsByWeek: { [week: string]: Question[] } = {
  week1: [
{
  question: "Which country played a key role in proposing the concept of “Gross National Happiness” as a scale for measuring the happiness level of a country?",
  options: ["China", "Bhutan", "USA", "Finland"],
  answer: "Bhutan",
},
{
  question: "Which of the following are some general characteristics of happy people?\n\nA. They are more productive and creative at work\nB. They have more gratitude and compassion\nC. They are good negotiators and leaders\nD. They are physically healthier and have good immunity",
  options: [
    "Only A and B are true",
    "Only A, B and D are true",
    "Only B and D are true",
    "All of these are true"
  ],
  answer: "All of these are true",
},
{
  question: "According to the thematic classification of the course “Science of happiness and wellbeing” which of the following come under ‘basics’ section?\n\nA. Creative music and art therapy for happiness\nB. Different tools and scales for measurement of happiness\nC. Relationship between money, material wealth and happiness\nD. If happiness is genetically determined",
  options: [
    "Only B and C are true",
    "Only B, C and D are true",
    "Only C and D are true",
    "Only A, B and D are true"
  ],
  answer: "Only C and D are true",
},
{
  question: "In early phases of civilization, happiness was demologically associated with luck. Is this statement true?",
  options: ["True", "False"],
  answer: "True",
},
{
  question: "Who defined Happiness as the “the experience of joy, contentment, or positive well-being, combined with a sense that one's life is good, meaningful, and worthwhile”?",
  options: ["Daniel Kahneman", "Ruut Venhooven", "Sonja Lyubomirsky", "Martin Seligman"],
  answer: "Sonja Lyubomirsky",
},
{
  question: "The term “Prasanna” mentioned in Bhagvat Purana as a term representing a particular shade of happiness is a\n\nA. Non-peak experience\nB. Long term experience\nC. External experience\nD. Spiritual experience",
  options: [
    "Only A and B are true",
    "Only A, B and D are true",
    "All of these are true",
    "Only B and D are true"
  ],
  answer: "Only B and D are true",
},
{
  question: "In the context of an integral relationship between environment and happiness, the story of Sarpa Satra by Arun Kolatkar deals with the conflicts regarding the destruction of Khandava forest between _____________.",
  options: [
    "Lord Indra and Lord Krishna",
    "Lord Shiva and Lord Krishna",
    "Lord Brahma and Lord Shiva",
    "Lord Indra and Lord Brahma"
  ],
  answer: "Lord Indra and Lord Krishna",
},
{
  question: "Which among the following are examples of ambivalent feelings associated with happiness?\n\nA. Sensitivity to mystery\nB. Euphoria\nC. Romantic longing\nD. Hope or anticipation",
  options: [
    "Only A and C are true",
    "Only A, C and D are true",
    "Only C and D are true",
    "All are true"
  ],
  answer: "Only A, C and D are true",
},
{
  question: "The idea of fundamental dimensions of well-being, which is primarily experienced through feelings, influenced by relationships and cultivated through personal development, is given by __________.",
  options: ["Tim Lomas", "Martin Luther King", "George MacKerron", "Sonja Lyubomirshy"],
  answer: "Tim Lomas",
},
{
  question: "In which of the following religious traditions, “Knowing the self as a Soul different from the body” is the first and necessary condition for Happiness?",
  options: ["Christian", "Jainism", "Islamic", "Buddhism"],
  answer: "Jainism",
},
{
  question: "According to the Pancha Kosha theory, choose the correct sequence for the five koshas from lower to higher state of consciousness.",
  options: [
    "Vijnanamaya Kosha, Manomaya koshha, Pranamaya kosha, Annamaya kosha, Anandamaya Kosha",
    "Manomaya koshha, Pranamaya kosha, Annamaya kosha, Anandamaya Kosha, Vijnanamaya Kosha",
    "Anandamaya Kosha, Manomaya kosha, Pranamaya kosha, Annamaya kosha, Vijnanamaya Kosha",
    "Annamaya Kosha, Pranamaya Kosha, Manomaya koshha, Vijnanamaya kosha, Anandamaya kosha"
  ],
  answer: "Annamaya Kosha, Pranamaya Kosha, Manomaya koshha, Vijnanamaya kosha, Anandamaya kosha",
},
{
  question: "“The Myth of Sisyphus” is a book written by _________ where he focused on the concept of admitting death as the only permanent and accepting life as absurd.",
  options: ["Albert Camus", "Franz Kafka", "Alain de Botton", "Hildegard of Bingen"],
  answer: "Albert Camus",
},
{
  question: "Extremely happy people can be distracted and may not be creative or innovative. Is the statement true?",
  options: ["True", "False"],
  answer: "True",
},
{
  question: "Which among the following are key indicators of unhappiness?\n\nA. Social isolation\nB. Lack of eye contact\nC. Regular sleep cycle\nD. Recurring negative emotion",
  options: [
    "Only A and B are true",
    "Only A, B and D are true",
    "Only B and D are true",
    "Only A and D are true"
  ],
  answer: "Only A, B and D are true",
},
{
  question: "Adaptation of humans to any positive and negative feelings and eventually those feelings turning to the baseline level is known as",
  options: [
    "Preconceived notion",
    "Hedonic adaptation",
    "Cerebral determination",
    "Base level validation"
  ],
  answer: "Hedonic adaptation",
}
],
week2: [
{
  question: "Adaptation of humans to any positive and negative feelings and eventually those feelings turning to the baseline level is known as:",
  options: [
    "Preconceived notion",
    "Hedonic adaptation",
    "Cerebral determination",
    "Base level validation",
  ],
  answer: "Hedonic adaptation",
},
{
  question: "Which of the following are primary parameters of happiness?\n\na. Autonomy\nb. Affluence\nc. Assimilation\nd. Appreciation",
  options: [
    "Only a and b are correct",
    "Only b and c are correct",
    "Only a, b and d are correct",
    "All of these are correct",
  ],
  answer: "Only a, b and d are correct",
},
{
  question: "Choice over compulsion is one of the major guiding philosophies of the course science of happiness and wellbeing. Is this statement true?",
  options: ["True", "False"],
  answer: "True",
},
{
  question: "Which among the following are some of the contributions of happiness in life?\n\na. Happiness offers us meaning and purpose in life\nb. Happiness helps us to discover new passions, generate curiosity about life, environment and others\nc. Happiness helps us to build stronger coping skill & emotional resources\nd. Happiness reduces life risks and our tolerance to uncertainty\ne. Happiness keeps us healthy – both mentally & physically",
  options: [
    "Only b, c and d are correct",
    "Only a, b, c and e are correct",
    "Only a, b, d and e are correct",
    "All of these are correct",
  ],
  answer: "Only a, b, c and e are correct",
},
{
  question: "A pan cultural study done by ___________ across 136 countries revealed that purchasing a gift for someone else enhances our happiness level more than receiving a gift from someone.",
  options: ["Park et al.", "Kahneman et al.", "Seligman et al.", "Dunn et al."],
  answer: "Dunn et al.",
},
{
  question: "A two week’s vacation is twice as good as a one week vacation. Is the statement true?",
  options: ["True", "False"],
  answer: "False",
},
{
  question: "Some of the following are the key findings of a study done by Bastian et al. (2014). Which of them are true?\n\na. Pain forms social bonds\nb. Pain captures our attention\nc. Relief from pain helps us recognize pleasure\nd. Pain is inevitable but suffering is optional",
  options: [
    "Only c and d are true",
    "Only b, c and d are true",
    "Only a, b and d are true",
    "All of these are true",
  ],
  answer: "All of these are true",
},
{
  question: "Consumer behaviour, according to Daniel Kahneman, is primarily dominated by __________.",
  options: ["Memory", "Moment", "Money", "Missing out"],
  answer: "Moment",
},
{
  question: "Which of the following options correctly explains the concept of “betweenness”?",
  options: [
    "When we don’t mind being unhappy if everybody around us is unhappy",
    "When we anticipate that others around us are happy amidst a sense of self-unhappiness",
    "When we believe that we can be happy if others are happy, even if we have to compromise our own happiness for the sake of others’ happiness",
    "When we believe that our personal pleasure is the most important thing, even if it comes at the cost of others",
  ],
  answer: "When we believe that we can be happy if others are happy, even if we have to compromise our own happiness for the sake of others’ happiness",
},
{
  question: "Anil and Raj are two college friends and have recently completed their Bachelor’s degree. Both of them are brilliant students and often used to compete for the first position in the exams. Recently, Anil has received two decent job offers, one of which is offering a placement in his hometown and a higher salary than the other. Yesterday, they met accidentally at a cafe and Raj revealed that he has received five job offers and all of them are equivalently tempting in terms of salary and other benefits. While deciding on the job offer which each of them shall accept, _____________.",
  options: [
    "Anil will be happier than Raj",
    "Raj will be happier than Anil",
    "Both of them will be equally happy",
    "None of them will be happy",
  ],
  answer: "Anil will be happier than Raj",
},
{
  question: "‘We are not designed for happiness or unhappiness…but to strive for the goals that evolution has built us into’. This is a statement by __________.",
  options: ["Daniel Kahneman", "Martin Seligman", "Daniel Nettle", "Charles Darwin"],
  answer: "Daniel Nettle",
},
{
  question: "According to the evolutionary theory of emotions, our survival is possible because of adaptation. In this context, which of the following statements are true?\n\na. Survival in early days was binary; one person’s gain was to other person’s loss (e.g., finding mate)\nb. Happiness is a proximate goal (success) while anxiety is a distant goal (failure) to achieve adaptation\nc. While happiness has benefits; discontent does not have any benefit and it is also not necessary for survival",
  options: [
    "Only b and c are true",
    "Only a and b are true",
    "Only a and c are true",
    "All of these are true",
  ],
  answer: "Only a and b are true",
},
{
  question: "Which of the following statements are true in the context of happiness and pleasure?\n\na. Pleasure is more associated with the activation of reward-motivation circuit in the brain and the release of dopamine; whereas happiness and contentment is more associated with the release of serotonin\nb. Pleasure is short-term whereas happiness is long term\nc. Pleasure is addictive i.e., it always makes us think that 'I want more!' whereas happiness is non-addictive and makes us think that 'It’s enough!'\nd. Pleasure is typically experienced alone, whereas happiness inspires giving and generally enhances in shared experiences",
  options: [
    "Only a, b and c are true",
    "Only b, c and d are true",
    "Only a, c and d are true",
    "All of these are true",
  ],
  answer: "All of these are true",
},
{
  question: "Which among the following four aspects does NOT contribute to the formation of our belief system?",
  options: ["Stereotypes", "Opinions", "Perceptions", "Meta"],
  answer: "Stereotypes",
},
{
  question: "In 2021, Jeremy Clifton proposed the concept of “Primal belief” which determines an individual’s most basic belief about the general characteristics of the world. According to this theory, which of the following are the secondary primal beliefs?\n\na. Alive (vs. mechanistic)\nb. Enticing (vs. dull)\nc. Safe (vs. dangerous)\nd. Good (vs. bad)",
  options: [
    "Only a, c and d are true",
    "Only a, b and c are true",
    "Only b, c and d are true",
    "All of these are true",
  ],
  answer: "Only a, b and c are true",
},
{
  question: "In 2015, Bruce Lipton, a molecular biologist, proposed five premises for “The biology of belief” in his book. According to his conjectures, which of the following are true?\n\na. The cell is like a human body & it can function without DNA\nb. Environment has no role in our genetic predisposition\nc. Perception of environment is not necessarily the reality and our belief acts as a filter in between\nd. Human beliefs can choose to perceive an environment as positive or negative which helps in release of different hormones (growth or protection)\ne. Based on our perception of environment, conditional activation of “Fight or Flight” response can occur as well as growth and protection hormone can be released which in turn can result in different gene unfolding",
  options: [
    "Only a, b, c and e are true",
    "Only b, c, d and e are true",
    "Only a, c, d and e are true",
    "Only a, b, d and e are true",
  ],
  answer: "Only a, c, d and e are true",
},
],
week3: [
  {
    question: "Some of the following are examples of personality disorders caused by lack of empathy. Which of them are true?\n\na. Sociopathy\nb. Narcissism\nc. Telepathy\nd. Psychopathy",
    options: [
      "Only a, b and c are true",
      "Only a, b and d are true",
      "Only b, c and d are true",
      "All of these are true",
    ],
    answer: "Only a, b and d are true",
  },
  {
    question: "On Monday morning, Shefali comes to her classroom with a feeling of calmness and composure, as she has confidence that she will do good enough in her final exam viva. As she takes her seat, she notices Mrinmay, sitting right next to her, biting his nails, looking incredibly anxious and talking to others about the possible negative outcomes of the exam. Mrinmay has a history of severe test anxiety. Within minutes, Shefali finds herself in a nervous state, feeling her own heart racing and palms sweating and many of the friends sitting around them talking about the similar negative situations. This is an example of:",
    options: [
      "Psychopathy",
      "Sympathy",
      "Narcissism",
      "Emotional contagion",
    ],
    answer: "Emotional contagion",
  },
  {
    question: "The rain hammered against the bus windows, blurring the neon lights of the city into streaks of colour. Inside, huddled amongst the passengers, sat Sarah crying silently. Shame washed over her as she remembered the rejection email from her dream job, the final blow to an already difficult week. As Sarah fumbled for her bag, a gentle hand touched her shoulder. It was an elderly woman, her kind eyes crinkling at the corners. \"Rough day, dear?\" she asked softly. Sarah hesitated, then choked out a sob. The woman sat beside her, listening patiently as Sarah poured out her heart. She didn't offer empty platitudes or unsolicited advice, rather kept on listening to her emotional outburst silently. As Sarah reached her stop, she felt lighter, a weight lifted from her shoulders. \"Thank you,\" Sarah whispered, a genuine smile breaking through her tears. The woman smiled back, \"Just remember, dear, we all have these moments. Like all good things, bad things also do not last forever. But, when you’re down, don't be afraid to lean on others.\" Which of the following best demonstrates the elderly woman's reaction towards Sarah?",
    options: [
      "She was apathetic to Sarah and did not bother much about the situation",
      "She was sympathetic towards Sarah but could not give her any mental support",
      "She was compassionate towards Sarah and provided a safe space to express her emotions",
      "She was empathetic towards Sarah and could understand Sarah’s pain by putting herself in the situation",
    ],
    answer: "She was compassionate towards Sarah and provided a safe space to express her emotions",
  },
  {
    question: "The concept of “Moral disengagement” is proposed by:",
    options: [
      "Albert Bandura",
      "Martin Seligman",
      "Bertrand Russell",
      "Sigmund Freud",
    ],
    answer: "Albert Bandura",
  },
  {
    question: "Some of the following concepts are correct in the context of morality, in general. Which of them are true?\n\na. Morally grounded individuals are well-adjusted\nb. Change in moral standard is possible, if it is not a cardinal trait\nc. Morality develops as we grow old\nd. Biology & morality are mutually inclusive and the pre-frontal lobe is the locus for moral judgment",
    options: [
      "Only a, b and d are true",
      "Only a and c are true",
      "Only b, c and d are true",
      "Only b and d are true",
    ],
    answer: "Only b and d are true",
  },
  {
    question: "Cultural variations do not affect the constructs of moral standards. Is the statement true?",
    options: [
      "True",
      "False",
    ],
    answer: "False",
  },
  {
    question: "Heteronym in literature refers to one or more imaginary character(s) created by a writer to write in different styles. Which of the following poets used heteronyms in literature exhaustively?",
    options: [
      "William Wordsworth",
      "Fernando Pessoa",
      "John Keats",
      "Camilo Pessanha",
    ],
    answer: "Fernando Pessoa",
  },
  {
    question: "Who wrote the story about the young man, Siddharth, who used to say “I can think, I can wait, I can fast”?",
    options: [
      "Heinrich Heine",
      "Thomas Mann",
      "Hermann Hesse",
      "Freidrich Schiller",
    ],
    answer: "Hermann Hesse",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following attributes can be associated with the Self?\n\na. Sorted\nb. Divided\nc. Conflicted\nd. Unified",
    options: [
      "Only a and c are true",
      "Only b and d are true",
      "Only b and c are true",
      "None of these are true",
    ],
    answer: "Only b and c are true",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following factors is/are intrinsic driver(s) or reason(s) of prosocial behaviour?\n\na. Values\nb. Peer pressure\nc. Warm glow\nd. Career ambition",
    options: [
      "Only a is true",
      "Only a and b are true",
      "Only a and c are true",
      "All of these are true",
    ],
    answer: "Only a and c are true",
  },
  {
    question: "Veena is attending a charity event where people are pledging donations to an NGO for child healthcare and education. She is unsure of the ideal amount of donation, but she observes that many other people around her are pledging to donate various amounts of money. Seeing this, Veena, who has been indifferent from the beginning and unsure about the amount which she shall donate, suddenly declares her support for this cause, and goes on to donate a small amount. Which psychological phenomenon primarily describes Veena’s reaction?",
    options: [
      "Sunk cost fallacy",
      "Bandwagon effect",
      "Cognitive dissonance",
      "Groupthink",
    ],
    answer: "Bandwagon effect",
  },
  {
    question: "The Prisoner's Dilemma reflects:",
    options: [
      "The process of deciding punishments for crimes involving multiple criminals",
      "The importance of always trusting your friends",
      "The power of luck and random chance in decision-making",
      "The tension between individual and others’ benefits in various situations",
    ],
    answer: "The tension between individual and others’ benefits in various situations",
  },
  {
    question: "Virtues are not generalizable across various traditions. Is the statement true?",
    options: [
      "True",
      "False",
    ],
    answer: "False",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following are subcomponents of the virtue ‘Courage’ as identified by Peterson and Seligman, and also play very important roles in the context of leadership?\n\na. Prudence\nb. Self-regulation\nc. Perseverance\nd. Honesty",
    options: [
      "Only a, b and d are true",
      "Only a and b are true",
      "Only b, c and d are true",
      "Only c and d are true",
    ],
    answer: "Only c and d are true",
  },
  {
    question: "Some of the following activities are more likely to contribute to the \"Relationship\" element of the PERMA model of wellbeing proposed by famous American psychologist Martin Seligman. Which of them are true?\n\na. Showing your appreciation for work colleagues\nb. Organising catch-ups and get-togethers with family or friends, in person or online\nc. Watching your favourite TV show at home alone after dinner\nd. Volunteering in a blood donation camp in your community\ne. Practicing playing a musical instrument",
    options: [
      "Only a, b and d are true",
      "Only a and b are true",
      "Only b, c and d are true",
      "Only c and d are true",
    ],
    answer: "Only a, b and d are true",
  },
  {
    question: "Adaptation of humans to any positive and negative feelings and eventually those feelings turning to the baseline level is known as:",
    options: [
      "Preconceived notion",
      "Hedonic adaptation",
      "Cerebral determination",
      "Base level validation",
    ],
    answer: "Hedonic adaptation",
  },
],
  week4:[
    {
      "question": "Which among the following factors are some of the components related to community cohesiveness in urban areas?\n\na. Freedom\nb. Support\nc. Interference\nd. Festivals",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only a, b and d are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, b and d are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is NOT a categorical division of relationships based on kinship?",
      "options": [
        "Family",
        "Romance",
        "Equality",
        "Community"
      ],
      "answer": "Equality"
    },
    {
      "question": "Family and spouse relations have a greater significance on a person’s well-being than friends and community members. Is the statement true?",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "Individuals having connections with influential people, those who have further influential connections, belong to the ____________ region of relationship networks?",
      "options": [
        "Peripheral",
        "Central",
        "Subsequent central",
        "Subsequent peripheral"
      ],
      "answer": "Central"
    },
    {
      "question": "Morality resides in the groups rather than individuals. Is the statement true?",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "If Anna and Becky are unknown to each other and reside in opposite parts of the world, what is the maximum number of other people required in between them to establish a connection between Anna and Becky?",
      "options": [
        "Three",
        "Six",
        "Five",
        "Nine"
      ],
      "answer": "Five"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the context of the question if money can buy us happiness, some of the following statements are the findings of the research carried out by Daniel Kahneman and Angus Deaton in 2010. Which of them are true?\n\na. The quality of the respondents’ everyday emotional experiences did not improve beyond $75,000 a year\nb. There is little evidence of an income threshold at which experienced & evaluative wellbeing diverged\nc. Proportional differences in money matter the same to everyone\nd. Beyond $75,000, money is important for life evaluation, but does not contribute positively in emotional wellbeing",
      "options": [
        "Only a and d are true",
        "Only b and c are true",
        "Only a and c are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a and d are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "People may contribute more to society when they have less wealth themselves. This inference is driven from the study conducted by _____________.",
      "options": [
        "Angus Deaton",
        "Matthew Killingsworth",
        "Erik Erikson",
        "Lindsay Dodgson"
      ],
      "answer": "Lindsay Dodgson"
    },
    {
      "question": "Money and happiness are not directly connected because _____________.",
      "options": [
        "Money has intrinsic value while happiness depends on extrinsic value",
        "Money has extrinsic value while happiness depends on intrinsic value",
        "Both money and happiness have extrinsic value but their importance varies in accordance with events",
        "Wealth and happiness are often found together"
      ],
      "answer": "Money has extrinsic value while happiness depends on intrinsic value"
    },
    {
      "question": "Learned optimism, a phenomenon proposed by Martin Seligman, is based upon research on ….\n\na. Learned helplessness\nb. Attributional style\nc. Explanatory Pessimism\nd. Optimistic bias",
      "options": [
        "Only a and b are true",
        "Only b and c are true",
        "Only b and d are true",
        "Only a and d are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a and b are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "For the people with a positive belief system, gene unfolding will be different from those having a negative belief system. Is this statement true?",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "answer": "True"
    },
    {
      "question": "Some of the following are symptoms of optimistic bias. Which of these are true?\n\na. Change in objective reality\nb. Reduced precautionary measures\nc. Reduced harmful behaviors\nd. Temporal discounting",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only a, b and d are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, b and d are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "A fMRI study revealed that the same locus of the brain responds to both social rejection and physical pain and the area is _________.",
      "options": [
        "Anterior cingulate gyrus",
        "Amygdala",
        "Hippocampus",
        "Broca’s area"
      ],
      "answer": "Anterior cingulate gyrus"
    },
    {
      "question": "Belongingness is a basic need which has both physical and emotional aspects. The emotional aspect of belongingness is called ______________.",
      "options": [
        "Intimacy",
        "Compassion",
        "Altruism",
        "Connectedness"
      ],
      "answer": "Connectedness"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following cases are examples of the concept called “senseless act of beauty”?\n\na. A man suddenly saving a person unknown to him from an impending train accident without any future expectations, even risking his own life\nb. A man buying a new house and medical insurances for his wife and children with a large share of his savings\nc. A woman who stopped her car while driving to give water to a thirsty monkey sitting on the roadside\nd. A crowd at a concert spontaneously helping a person sitting on a wheelchair to watch the show without obstruction by lifting him up in the air",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only a and d are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, c and d are true"
    }
  ],
  week5 :[
    {
      "question": "Which among the following are some reasons for which we fail to communicate happiness?\n\na. We fail to listen to others\nb. We make incorrect assumptions\nc. We fail to express nonverbally\nd. We fail to perceive ourselves",
      "options": [
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "Only a, b and d are true",
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, b and c are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to Albert Mehrabian’s theory of non-verbal communication (1972), what percentage of the communication is carried through non-verbal components?",
      "options": [
        "93 percent",
        "55 percent",
        "7 percent",
        "38 percent"
      ],
      "answer": "93 percent"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are some channels of non-verbal behavior, through which we communicate and express ourselves knowingly or unknowingly?\n\na. Gazing behavior\nb. Interpersonal space or proxemics\nc. Facial expression of emotions\nd. Gestures or kinesics",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "All of these are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is NOT an impediment for resilience?\n\ni. The tendency to always stay in comfort zone\nii. The ability of self-regulation\niii. Having an external locus of control for adverse situations\niv. Not considering multiple possibilities at any situation",
      "options": [
        "The tendency to always stay in comfort zone",
        "The ability of self-regulation",
        "Having an external locus of control for adverse situations",
        "Not considering multiple possibilities at any situation"
      ],
      "answer": "The ability of self-regulation"
    },
    {
      "question": "According to the 'post-traumatic growth' model, many individuals who experience adversity commonly report some of the following behavioral changes in life. Which of these are true?\n\na. Decreased empathy and compassion for others\nb. Finding deeper meaning and purpose in life\nc. Increased appreciation for personal strengths",
      "options": [
        "Only a and b are true",
        "Only b and c are true",
        "Only a and c are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only b and c are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Coming from a country with very little snow, Australia’s Alisa Camplin didn't even take up skiing until she was 20 years old, in 1994. Eight years later, when she was competing in the 2002 Winter Olympic Games, she was feeling severe pain in both of her ankles. After an X-ray of her feet the doctors were stunned to see that what she thought was bad bruising to her ankles actually turned out to be two fractures. The doctors advised her not to compete as she was not fit enough for a high-performance sport like skiing. But, she went on to consult a psychologist and following her advice, Camplin competed and made her way to the top of the podium as the Olympic champion. In fact, during her career Camplin dealt with two broken ankles, two knee reconstructions, nine cracked ribs, and a number of concussions, and finally lost her first child to congenital heart disease. But, later she also became World champion and till date, continues to coach the Australian Skiing Team. This is a classic example of _____________.",
      "options": [
        "An irresponsible behaviour",
        "A recoiling behaviour",
        "A resilient behaviour",
        "An over-reactive behaviour"
      ],
      "answer": "A resilient behaviour"
    },
    {
      "question": "Innovation indexes for countries are measured by _____________.",
      "options": [
        "World Information Prosperity Organization",
        "World Innovation Index Organization",
        "World Innovation Property Organization",
        "World Intellectual Property Organization"
      ],
      "answer": "World Intellectual Property Organization"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements are correct in the context of structured innovation?\n\na. It comes out of an expert knowledge system where competent people use relevant technologies to innovate something\nb. Controlled access to knowledge & high-quality net-worked infra-structure\nc. This type of innovation does not originate from a socially recognized need\nd. It needs the support of a favourable economics and risk capital",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are correct",
        "Only a, b and d are correct",
        "Only b, c and d are correct",
        "Only a, c and d are correct"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, b and d are correct"
    },
    {
      "question": "Double decker living root bridges are one of the most famous tourist attractions in Meghalaya, where people used the living roots of rubber trees to build those bridges over streams and canals. These bridges not only allow pedestrians to cross the streams, they can also carry the loads of light vehicles like bi-cycles or motorbikes. Which of the following factors are true in the context of innovation of those bridges?\n\na. Indigenous\nb. Deductive\nc. Inexpensive\nd. Iterative",
      "options": [
        "Only a and c are true",
        "Only a, b and d are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, c and d are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "The concept of 'cognitive appraisal' emphasises the role of __________.",
      "options": [
        "Genetics in determining individual stress responses",
        "External stressors directly causing physiological reactions",
        "Personal interpretations and beliefs in influencing stress impact",
        "Automatic and unconscious stress responses regardless of context"
      ],
      "answer": "Personal interpretations and beliefs in influencing stress impact"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following are common markers of chronic stress in everyday life?\n\na. Overreacting to small problems\nb. Inability to concentrate\nc. Easily getting hurt\nd. Always worrying about something",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "All of these are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Conflict between an individual's logical and emotional judgments is called _____________.",
      "options": [
        "Decidophobia",
        "Necrophobia",
        "Emetophobia",
        "Aerophobia"
      ],
      "answer": "Decidophobia"
    },
    {
      "question": "A person suffering from greater than normal stress is likely to show greater tolerance towards uncertainty and ambiguity than others. Is this statement true?",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "As part of various coping strategies under stress, which of the following factors one must try to unlearn?\n\na. The desire to have control over everything\nb. Overestimation of threat potential\nc. Underestimating the process while focusing on the goal\nd. Fear of loss of identity while changing habits",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "All of these are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Some of the following coping strategies have been found to be extremely effective for managing daily stress. Which of them are true?\n\na. Engaging in regular physical activity (e.g., exercise, yoga)\nb. Practising mindfulness and relaxation techniques (e.g., meditation, deep breathing)\nc. Seeking social support and connecting with loved ones\nd. Establishing small, realistic goals and not taking big decisions\ne. Self-medication with various substances like alcohol or drugs",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b, c and d are true",
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only a, b, d and e are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, b and c are true"
    }
  ],
  week6:[
    {
      "question": "\"New age poor\" is a coinage we have heard frequently during COVID 19 pandemic. This particular type of lifestyle change signifies ___________.",
      "options": [
        "The lack of freedom due to restriction of movements",
        "The lack of ways of spending money although having enough money",
        "The lack of sense of safety due to fear of viral contamination",
        "The lack of time spent in natural environment due to overindulgence upon technology"
      ],
      "answer": "The lack of ways of spending money although having enough money"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are true in the context of changing behaviour and developing new habits?\n\na. Small, incremental improvements make habit stronger rather than drastic action\nb. New habits develop by pressure or coercion rather than by commitment\nc. Human behaviour does not change every day; we need to rewire the brain\nd. It takes 21 days to dissolve an old mental image",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "Only a, b and d are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, c and d are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following behavioural challenges were commonly observed during the COVID 19 pandemic?\n\na. Social facilitation\nb. Belongingness barrier\nc. Proximity stress\nd. Compassion fatigue",
      "options": [
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only b, c and d are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of the eight limbs mentioned in Patanjali’s Yoga Sutra is Pratyāhāra. What does it signify?",
      "options": [
        "To put on certain restrictions on oneself",
        "To follow certain rules in our lives",
        "To withdraw our mind from external disturbances",
        "To control our breathing process"
      ],
      "answer": "To withdraw our mind from external disturbances"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the three kinds of meditations most commonly practised in Bhutan for increasing self-awareness and mindfulness?",
      "options": [
        "Meditation with focus upon breathing, gazing and visualisation",
        "Meditation with focus upon gazing, chanting and body movements",
        "Meditation with focus upon breathing, chanting and body movements",
        "Meditation with focus upon chanting, images and words"
      ],
      "answer": "Meditation with focus upon breathing, gazing and visualisation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements are true in the context of meditation or yoga?\n\na. Meditation essentially means mind-body integration\nb. Meditation can be done with a focus on either breath or image, words, sound\nc. Meditation emphasises on maintaining a non-judgmental awareness\nd. Meditation can be of both long and short duration",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "Only a, b and d are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "All of these are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Many studies suggest that prolonged exposure towards practising meditation results in ___________________.",
      "options": [
        "Enhanced emotional intelligence and reduced concentration",
        "Enhanced concentration and unchanged emotional intelligence",
        "Enhanced emotional intelligence and enhanced concentration",
        "Enhanced concentration and reduced emotional intelligence"
      ],
      "answer": "Enhanced emotional intelligence and enhanced concentration"
    },
    {
      "question": "A study by a group of researchers from Harvard University revealed that mindfulness practice can result in reduction or shrinking of the __________ in the human brain.",
      "options": [
        "Occipital lobe",
        "Amygdala",
        "Hypothalamus",
        "Prefrontal cortex"
      ],
      "answer": "Amygdala"
    },
    {
      "question": "The book ____________ by Chade-Meng Tan primarily focuses upon the scientific validations of efficacies mindfulness have in improving mental and physical health as well as its practice.",
      "options": [
        "Search Inside Yourself",
        "Joy on Demand",
        "Mindfulness Meditation - Cultivating the Wisdom of Your Body and Mind",
        "Wherever You Go, There You Are"
      ],
      "answer": "Search Inside Yourself"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is NOT an example of non-heuristic thinking?",
      "options": [
        "A professional lawyer arranging the defence argument of a court case using step-by-step logical reasoning supported by various evidences",
        "A professional skier finding the best possible route to ski down a snowy mountain in the middle of an avalanche",
        "A professional biologist conducting a longitudinal scientific experiment with precise controls and measurements",
        "A professional historian analysing a historical event using detailed primary sources"
      ],
      "answer": "A professional skier finding the best possible route to ski down a snowy mountain in the middle of an avalanche"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the context of intuitive thinking, who made the following comment “Our derivative knowledge of truths consists of everything that we can deduce from self-evident truths by the use of self-evident principles of deduction”?",
      "options": [
        "Albert Einstein",
        "Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi",
        "A J Ayer",
        "Bertrand Russell"
      ],
      "answer": "Bertrand Russell"
    },
    {
      "question": "John, who has been practising music since his childhood, is an expert professional guitar player. When he was teaching his students, it was found that even if a student is playing the melody of a song which John has never heard before and do not know how the melody of notes progress in the song, he was able to play the correct chords along with it. Also, he could understand if the student was going off tune while playing the song on the guitar. This is a classic example of _________.",
      "options": [
        "Intuitive thinking",
        "Analytical thinking",
        "Creative thinking",
        "Flow"
      ],
      "answer": "Intuitive thinking"
    },
    {
      "question": "Hanna says to Charles, “Hey look, that man standing on the other side of the road is tall like a mountain!”. This is an example of ___________.",
      "options": [
        "Insight",
        "Intuition",
        "Analogy",
        "Schema"
      ],
      "answer": "Analogy"
    },
    {
      "question": "The framework of ‘six thinking hats’ proposed by Edward de Bono essentially encourages convergent thinking. Is this statement true?",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "answer": "False"
    },
    {
      "question": "A group of friends, planning a weekend getaway, decided to visit a hill station. While exploring the area, they came across an adventure park offering various thrilling activities. As they stood at the base of a steep mountain, looking up at the zip-lining platform, opinions began to diverge. Ravi, always cautious, expressed his concern, \"Zip-lining seems dangerous. What if the harness breaks? It’s too risky for me.\" On the other hand, Priya, the adventurous one, was excited, \"Zip-lining is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity! It's a chance to overcome our fears and experience the thrill.\" Sam, the practical one, suggested, \"Let's consider the safety measures first. If the park has a good safety record, we can give it a try.\" Finally, Ria, the peacemaker, proposed, \"Maybe we can try something less risky together, like trekking or rock climbing. We can enjoy the outdoors without taking unnecessary risks.\"\n\nFollowing the above passage match the people on the right-hand side with their thinking styles on the left-hand side.\n\na. Ravi\nb. Priya\nc. Sam\nd. Ria\n\n1. Cautious thinking\n2. Peacemaker thinking\n3. Adventurous thinking\n4. Practical thinking",
      "options": [
        "a-1, b-4, c-3, d-2",
        "a-3, b-4, c-1, d-2",
        "a-3, b-1, c-2, d-4",
        "a-2, b-3, c-1, d-4"
      ],
      "answer": "a-3, b-4, c-1, d-2"
    }
  ],
  week7:[{
    "question": "Two school friends, Deepak and Nandini started working at two different companies after completing their masters’ degree and they decided to meet after a long time. During their reunion they were discussing their work experience under their bosses. Deepak works at a private bank. He told his friends that his manager is laser-focused on the performance of his employees, and establishes predetermined incentives usually in the form of monetary reward for success and disciplinary action for failure. He meets each member of the team bi-weekly to discuss ways the team can meet and exceed monthly company goals to get their bonus. Each of the top 10 performers in the district receives a monetary reward. On the other hand, Nandini, a graphic designer, shared that she is not very happy with her current work environment. Her boss is focused almost entirely on results and efficiency. He often makes decisions alone or with a small, trusted group and expects employees to do exactly what they’re asked to do, more like a military commander. Nandini feels that this kind of rigid environment can prove to be helpful for some undisciplined colleagues, whereas the rest of them are struggling with their creative tasks. Deepak’s case is an example of ________, whereas the leadership style of Nandini’s boss can be best described as ____________. (Fill in the blanks)",
    "options": [
      "i. Transformational leadership and Transactional leadership",
      "ii. Transactional leadership and Authoritarian leadership",
      "iii. Laissez Faire leadership and Transformational leadership",
      "iv. Authoritarian Leadership and Laissez Faire leadership"
    ],
    "answer": "ii. Transactional leadership and Authoritarian leadership"
  },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following best describes the primary function of 'self-regulation' in emotional intelligence?\n\na. Recognising and understanding one's own emotions\nb. Managing and controlling impulsive emotions and behaviours\nc. Building and maintaining social networks\nd. Identifying and empathising with the emotions of others",
      "options": [
        "Recognising and understanding one's own emotions",
        "Managing and controlling impulsive emotions and behaviours",
        "Building and maintaining social networks",
        "Identifying and empathising with the emotions of others"
      ],
      "answer": "Managing and controlling impulsive emotions and behaviours"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does 'relationship management' within emotional intelligence contribute to leadership effectiveness?\n\na. It focuses solely on the leader's ability to empathise with others\nb. It enhances the ability to communicate emotions nonverbally\nc. It involves the skill to inspire, influence, and develop others while managing conflict\nd. It solely requires the identification and analysis of group dynamics",
      "options": [
        "It focuses solely on the leader's ability to empathise with others",
        "It enhances the ability to communicate emotions nonverbally",
        "It involves the skill to inspire, influence, and develop others while managing conflict",
        "It solely requires the identification and analysis of group dynamics"
      ],
      "answer": "It involves the skill to inspire, influence, and develop others while managing conflict"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role does empathy play in emotional intelligence?\n\na. It has no significant impact on emotional intelligence\nb. It helps individuals connect with others and understand their perspectives\nc. It leads to emotional detachment and apathy\nd. It fosters a self-centred and unsympathetic outlook",
      "options": [
        "It has no significant impact on emotional intelligence",
        "It helps individuals connect with others and understand their perspectives",
        "It leads to emotional detachment and apathy",
        "It fosters a self-centred and unsympathetic outlook"
      ],
      "answer": "It helps individuals connect with others and understand their perspectives"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can organisations best facilitate personal growth to enhance happiness at work?\n\na. Implementing annual performance reviews\nb. Encouraging peer competition\nc. Providing continuous learning opportunities\nd. Offering flexible work hours",
      "options": [
        "Implementing annual performance reviews",
        "Encouraging peer competition",
        "Providing continuous learning opportunities",
        "Offering flexible work hours"
      ],
      "answer": "Providing continuous learning opportunities"
    },
    {
      "question": "Some of the followings are misconceptions about attitude in a workplace. Which among these are true?\n\na. Feeling is cardinal in attitude change\nb. Competence reduces negative attitude\nc. Moral people have difficulty in staying loyal all the time\nd. Loyal people have better attitude towards change",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "Only a, b and d are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, c and d are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following ways are very effective in enhancing happiness at the workplace?\n\na. Encouraging organisational citizenship\nb. Focusing on meaningful engagements\nc. Building up a trust-based transparency among the employees\nd. Internal brand building",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "All of these are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Small and insignificant details in nudge messages can change human behaviour due to which of the following reason(s)?\n\na. They shift the focus of attention to a given direction\nb. They comprise of hidden messages that can’t be cracked easily\nc. They order the people to take actions in a particular way",
      "options": [
        "Only a is true",
        "Only a and c are true",
        "Only b and c are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a is true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Choices, in nudge behaviour, are made using which of the following factors?\n\na. Subconscious logic\nb. Covert knowledge\nc. Feeling and instinct\nd. Linear thought processes",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and c are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, b and c are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Match the following messages or actions on the left column with their respective persuasion message categories in the right column:\n\na. a-2\nb. b-1\nc. c-3\nd. d-4",
      "options": [
        "a-2, b-1, c-3, d-4",
        "a-3, b-4, c-2, d-1",
        "a-3, b-1, c-4, d-2",
        "a-2, b-1, c-4, d-3"
      ],
      "answer": "a-3, b-4, c-2, d-1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following parameters are part of the World Happiness Index?\n\na. Generosity\nb. Education\nc. Good governance\nd. Social support\ne. Healthy life expectancy",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and d are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "Only a, d and e are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, d and e are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following parameters are indicators of Psychological Wellbeing in the Gross National Happiness scale?\n\na. Spirituality\nb. Family\nc. Life satisfaction\nd. Safety\ne. Fundamental rights",
      "options": [
        "Only a, b and d are true",
        "Only b, c and d are true",
        "Only a and c are true",
        "Only a, c and e are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a and c are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "An 11-point scale called Cantril Ladder is used in Happiness measurement. A marking on 10 in the Cantril Ladder indicates _________________. (Fill in the blank)\n\na. Highest possible economic class\nb. Maximum possible stress\nc. Best possible life\nd. Highest possible freedom",
      "options": [
        "Highest possible economic class",
        "Maximum possible stress",
        "Best possible life",
        "Highest possible freedom"
      ],
      "answer": "Best possible life"
    },
    {
      "question": "Some of the following habits are extremely relevant in the context of leadership. Which of them are true?\n\na. Purpose for self and purpose for others\nb. Resisting constant changes\nc. Strive for perfection\nd. Ability to think in terms of creating a legacy beyond the self",
      "options": [
        "Only a and d are true",
        "Only b and c are true",
        "Only a, c and d are true",
        "Only a, b and d are true"
      ],
      "answer": "Only a, c and d are true"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statement/s is/are true regarding leadership?\n\na. Leadership is the action of leading a group of people or an organisation\nb. Leadership is the ability to influence others in order to achieve a goal\nc. Leadership is a continuous process of influencing behaviour",
      "options": [
        "Only a is true",
        "Only a and c are true",
        "Only a and b are true",
        "All of these are true"
      ],
      "answer": "All of these are true"
    }

],
    week8:[
        {
          "question": "Subjective experience recording is a ‘first person’ methodology of happiness research. Which of the following statements are true in the context of subjective experience?\n\na. It is exploratory\nb. It is experiential\nc. It is analytical\nd. It is qualitative",
          "options": [
            "Only b and d are true",
            "Only b, c and d are true",
            "Only a, b and d are true",
            "All of these are true"
          ],
          "answer": "Only a, b and d are true"
        },
        {
          "question": "While assessing a person’s emotions from the face using a thermal camera, which of the following biological attributes is measured as the parameter?\n\ni. Muscular movements around the face\nii. Vascularity around the face\niii. Pupil dilation\niv. Jaw line movement",
          "options": [
            "Only a, b and c are true",
            "Only a, b and d are true",
            "Only b, c and d are true",
            "All of these are true"
          ],
          "answer": "Only a, b and d are true"
        },
        {
          "question": "The following self-report techniques are used to examine the state of happiness in subjects. Indicate the ones that are termed as projective techniques?\n\na. Sentence completion\nb. Situation judgement test\nc. Picture sorting\nd. Thought listing",
          "options": [
            "Only a, c and d are true",
            "Only a, b and c are true",
            "Only b, c and d are true",
            "All of these are true"
          ],
          "answer": "Only a, c and d are true"
        },
        {
          "question": "“The true essence of advertising is to make customers want more. It is designed to make them restless, leaving little room for contentment”. This definition was proposed by ____________? (Fill in the blank)\n\ni. Mel Cruickshank\nii. Jonathan Trimble\niii. John Campbell\niv. Omaid Hiwaizi",
          "options": [
            "Mel Cruickshank",
            "Jonathan Trimble",
            "John Campbell",
            "Omaid Hiwaizi"
          ],
          "answer": "Omaid Hiwaizi"
        },
        {
          "question": "Some of the following aspects are harmful contributions of advertisements on our everyday lives. Which of them are true?\n\na. They make us buy more than we can afford\nb. They always make us compare ourselves with others\nc. They always make our lives richer in terms of material things\nd. They create desires when we have none",
          "options": [
            "Only a, b and d are true",
            "Only a, c and d are true",
            "Only a, b and c are true",
            "All of these are true"
          ],
          "answer": "Only a, b and d are true"
        },
        {
          "question": "An advertisement features a group of people stranded in a rural village after a massive landslide caused by torrential rain. One of them is severely injured and needs emergency medical attention. In a place like this there is no well-developed hospital and the road connectivity is almost cut off. After a brief struggle, just before passing away, the man takes out a plastic wrapped document from under his shirt and hands it over to his crying wife beside him. The next scene jumps to one month after this incident, where it is shown that the wife is rebuilding their home out of scratch and remembering the last moments with her husband, and the piece of document which he gave her turned out to be his life insurance policy. Finally, the ad ends with the note that after his demise, how the said life insurance company acted promptly to give her the money and stood beside her during her misery. This is an example of a ___________. (Fill in the blank)\n\ni. Positive ad giving a negative message\nii. Positive ad giving a positive message\niii. Negative ad giving a negative message\niv. Negative ad giving a positive message",
          "options": [
            "Positive ad giving a negative message",
            "Positive ad giving a positive message",
            "Negative ad giving a negative message",
            "Negative ad giving a positive message"
          ],
          "answer": "Negative ad giving a positive message"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following technologies were evolved during World War II?\n\na. Blood transfusion\nb. Antibiotic treatment\nc. Supercomputers\nd. Radar technology",
          "options": [
            "Only a, b and c are true",
            "Only a, b and d are true",
            "Only b, c and d are true",
            "All of these are true"
          ],
          "answer": "Only a, b and d are true"
        },
        {
          "question": "Sarah had always dreamed of owning a sleek, red automatic convertible. Coming to know this, Sarah’s boss, being extremely impressed by her dedicated and hard-working nature, gifts Sarah her dream car. The first few weeks were exhilarating. The wind in her hair, the envious glances, the pure joy of driving her prized possession were intoxicating. However, as the novelty wore off, so did the thrill. The initial excitement gradually transformed into a sense of normalcy. The once extraordinary car became just another mode of transportation for her. The mandatory long drives during every weekend and the thrill of the open road was gradually replaced by the monotony of daily commutes. After one and a half years she even started thinking about buying a new mountain bike for more adventure trips. What's the most likely explanation of Sarah’s thought process?\n\ni. The new car is not technologically advanced enough to be driven on any road condition\nii. The increasing work pressure at office is taking a toll on Sarah’s mental health\niii. Sarah is showing the symptoms of set point effect\niv. Sarah has unrealistic expectations from her boss",
          "options": [
            "The new car is not technologically advanced enough to be driven on any road condition",
            "The increasing work pressure at office is taking a toll on Sarah’s mental health",
            "Sarah is showing the symptoms of set point effect",
            "Sarah has unrealistic expectations from her boss"
          ],
          "answer": "Sarah is showing the symptoms of set point effect"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following factors are driving technologies in a particular direction?\n\na. Ability to take responsibilities\nb. Mental health apps and tools\nc. Power elements\nd. Ideologies",
          "options": [
            "Only a, b and c are true",
            "Only b, c and d are true",
            "Only a, b and d are true",
            "All of these are true"
          ],
          "answer": "Only b, c and d are true"
        },
        {
          "question": "Research shows that automated speech analysis can be used effectively during interviews for positive trait assessment of the candidates. According to their findings, compared to low dominance, a highly dominant voice will have _________________. (Fill in the blank)\n\ni. Lower number of pauses and lower average duration of pauses\nii. Higher number of pauses and higher average duration of pauses\niii. Higher number of pauses and lower average duration of pauses\niv. Lower number of pauses and higher average duration of pauses",
          "options": [
            "Lower number of pauses and lower average duration of pauses",
            "Higher number of pauses and higher average duration of pauses",
            "Higher number of pauses and lower average duration of pauses",
            "Lower number of pauses and higher average duration of pauses"
          ],
          "answer": "Higher number of pauses and lower average duration of pauses"
        },
        {
          "question": "Pinaki, a visual artist himself, tried to understand through scientific research if artists can predict where the viewers will look primarily while viewing their paintings. Using various measurement tools and techniques, he studied how the artists generally use certain visual strategies and anticipate that the viewers’ gazing behaviour will follow a certain pathway while looking at those paintings. Which of the following methods/tools he can use in this research?\n\na. Self-report surveys\nb. Eye tracking\nc. Computational method for image analysis\nd. Electrodermal activity through GSR",
          "options": [
            "Only a, b and c can be used",
            "Only b, c and d can be used",
            "Only a, c and d can be used",
            "All of these can be used"
          ],
          "answer": "Only a, b and c can be used"
        },
        {
          "question": "Suppose, you are conducting research where you wish to explore if (and how) a person’s emotion perception changes if they are already in a pre-induced happy or sad mood in comparison to a neutral state. Which of the following interventions can you use for mood induction in participants?\n\na. Music\nb. News\nc. Movies\nd. Virtual reality",
          "options": [
            "Only a and c can be used",
            "Only a, b and c can be used",
            "Only a, c and d can be used",
            "All of these can be used"
          ],
          "answer": "All of these can be used"
        },
        {
          "question": "Social innovations are open source in nature. Is this statement true?\n\ni. True\nii. False",
          "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "answer": "True"
        },
        {
          "question": "Some of the following are examples of social innovation initiatives across the globe. Which of them are true?\n\na. Braille printing for visually impaired individuals\nb. Self-driving cars\nc. Solar-powered lamps for remote communities\nd. Water purification tablets",
          "options": [
            "Only a, b and c are true",
            "Only a, c and d are true",
            "Only b, c and d are true",
            "All of these are true"
          ],
          "answer": "Only a, c and d are true"
        },
        {
          "question": "Mobile banking and financial services have changed the lives of the common people for the better, particularly in India where mobile money transfers have been embraced by millions of users who previously did not have access to banking services. This has enabled them to save money, make payments and receive remittances with ease, empowering them in ways that were not possible before. This is ___________. (Fill in the blank)\n\ni. A social innovation in healthcare\nii. A social innovation in business management\niii. A social innovation in community development\niv. A social innovation in education",
          "options": [
            "A social innovation in healthcare",
            "A social innovation in business management",
            "A social innovation in community development",
            "A social innovation in education"
          ],
          "answer": "A social innovation in community development"
        }

    ]
};
